<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Simon Naitram</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Simon Naitram</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Creative Destruction</title>
      <link>/weshouldallbeeconomists/2018/05/01/creative-destruction/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/weshouldallbeeconomists/2018/05/01/creative-destruction/</guid>
      <description>“Just because something works doesn’t mean it can’t be improved.” ~ Princess Shuri, Wakanda
 It was somewhere during my third watching of Black Panther that I realised what attracted me to Wakanda The Economy. It was the willingness to innovate, the desire for constant improvement, the idea that there’s always a better way. Overseen by a child or not, Wakanda’s technological advances were never-ending.
Why is Barbados, unlike Wakanda, so resistant to innovation?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We Should All Be Economists</title>
      <link>/weshouldallbeeconomists/2018/04/10/wsabe/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/weshouldallbeeconomists/2018/04/10/wsabe/</guid>
      <description>This blog is titled We Should All Be Economists because its purpose is to help you become an economist. Not a full-fledged practicing economist, but an engaged citizen who can discuss the merits of government policies and personal actions. This blog is to help you understand the silly economicky world around us, in real time.
We Should All Be Economists is driven by the idea that a more engaged, informed, and active society leads to better economic outcomes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s the Real Problem with Barbados?</title>
      <link>/weshouldallbeeconomists/2018/04/10/productivitybb/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/weshouldallbeeconomists/2018/04/10/productivitybb/</guid>
      <description>How have we managed to end up here again? It would be convenient to find a single person, party or group to blame. But convenience rarely points us to the truth, and what we face today is a far more fundamental failure of our society.
What is the fundamental economic problem? In a word: productivity. It’s one of those ethereal concepts that economists love to throw around. There’s plenty we don’t know about productivity, but there is plenty we agree on.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>