<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Simon Naitram</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Simon Naitram</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Protect Workers, Not Jobs</title>
      <link>/weshouldallbeeconomists/2018/05/30/protect-workers-not-jobs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/weshouldallbeeconomists/2018/05/30/protect-workers-not-jobs/</guid>
      <description>How would you feel if you lost your job? What if your job was taken by a computer, or a machine? I think you would be angry. I know I would be mad.
But our world changes quickly. We either change with it, or get left behind. Sometimes innovation changes the world so quickly that it knocks us down. And the fear of being knocked down might be holding us back.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don’t Get Tricked By Debt</title>
      <link>/weshouldallbeeconomists/2018/05/29/don-t-get-tricked-by-debt/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/weshouldallbeeconomists/2018/05/29/don-t-get-tricked-by-debt/</guid>
      <description>The first thing everyone wants to talk about when discussing Barbados’ problems is the government’s debt. Debt is fashionable. It’s easy to understand, and easy to blame. But is debt really the problem?
You’ll probably guess that I’m about to say no. Debt is a symptom. You don’t cure diseases by treating the symptoms.
Firstly, governments aren’t households. You cannot think about government debt in the same way you think about getting a loan from the bank to buy a new car.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A New Vision</title>
      <link>/weshouldallbeeconomists/2018/05/25/a-new-vision/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/weshouldallbeeconomists/2018/05/25/a-new-vision/</guid>
      <description>Does a new government represent a new beginning? I have no idea. I am sure however, that a new government represents a new chance to do things right.
We need a new vision. How do we see ourselves in 10 years? Go on, imagine what life will be like. Close your eyes, think of what you want for yourself, your family, your people, your country.
Now open your eyes. How do we get there?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creative Destruction</title>
      <link>/weshouldallbeeconomists/2018/05/01/creative-destruction/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/weshouldallbeeconomists/2018/05/01/creative-destruction/</guid>
      <description>“Just because something works doesn’t mean it can’t be improved.” ~ Princess Shuri, Wakanda
 It was somewhere during my third watching of Black Panther that I realised what attracted me to Wakanda The Economy. It was the willingness to innovate, the desire for constant improvement, the idea that there’s always a better way. Overseen by a child or not, Wakanda’s technological advances were never-ending.
Why is Barbados, unlike Wakanda, so resistant to innovation?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We Should All Be Economists</title>
      <link>/weshouldallbeeconomists/2018/04/10/wsabe/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/weshouldallbeeconomists/2018/04/10/wsabe/</guid>
      <description>This blog is titled We Should All Be Economists because its purpose is to help you become an economist. Not a full-fledged practicing economist, but an engaged citizen who can discuss the merits of government policies and personal actions. This blog is to help you understand the silly economicky world around us, in real time.
We Should All Be Economists is driven by the idea that a more engaged, informed, and active society leads to better economic outcomes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s the Real Problem with Barbados?</title>
      <link>/weshouldallbeeconomists/2018/04/10/productivitybb/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/weshouldallbeeconomists/2018/04/10/productivitybb/</guid>
      <description>How have we managed to end up here again? It would be convenient to find a single person, party or group to blame. But convenience rarely points us to the truth, and what we face today is a far more fundamental failure of our society.
What is the fundamental economic problem? In a word: productivity. It’s one of those ethereal concepts that economists love to throw around. There’s plenty we don’t know about productivity, but there is plenty we agree on.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>