<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Simon Naitram</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Simon Naitram</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A Proposal for Solving Public Transport</title>
      <link>/weshouldallbeeconomists/2019/10/25/a-proposal-for-solving-public-transport/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/weshouldallbeeconomists/2019/10/25/a-proposal-for-solving-public-transport/</guid>
      <description>Fixing Public Transport Public transport in Barbados is an urgent matter. We have around 63 cars per kilometre of road, and that was measured in 2004. We have the 12th highest rate of accidents per capita and 23rd for road fatalities per capita. We have the highest road density in the Western Hemisphere, and at 387 cars per 1,000 persons (4 cars for each 10 people), we are 20th on the list of cars per person.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Democratising Business</title>
      <link>/weshouldallbeeconomists/2019/05/16/democratising-business/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/weshouldallbeeconomists/2019/05/16/democratising-business/</guid>
      <description>You have a great business idea. You have a great business plan. You have the skills to execute. You are the ideal entrepreneur.
There’s only one thing missing—the money to start your business. In Barbados, where do you get that money?
I’ll hazard a quick guess—you don’t. Unless, of course, your family is rich. Or maybe you’re friends with rich people. Or you work for three decades to save up enough money to start your business.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#LessTaxesMoreCARICOMTravel</title>
      <link>/weshouldallbeeconomists/2019/04/23/lesstaxesmorecaricomtravel/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/weshouldallbeeconomists/2019/04/23/lesstaxesmorecaricomtravel/</guid>
      <description>“To divide and rule, is their only plan, their only plan. But I a no fool to let dem overcome” ~ Jah Cure, King in the Jungle (ft. Sizzla)
 For a generation, the governments of the Caribbean have obstructed the Caribbean project. There is one single thing that would change the game. It would bring the whole stupid wall crashing down.
Remove taxes on travel within CARICOM.
Taxes on inter-island travel make up exorbitant amounts of the cost of a ticket to travel within the Caribbean.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is the Increase in Bus Fare Justified?</title>
      <link>/weshouldallbeeconomists/2019/04/22/the-unfair-and-inefficient-350/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/weshouldallbeeconomists/2019/04/22/the-unfair-and-inefficient-350/</guid>
      <description>Everyone is wondering whether the increase in bus fare from $2 to $3.50 was justified. Was it the right decision? Should it have been kept at $2? Is there something else we could have done?
Let’s take a step-by-step economic look at the problem of public transport in Barbados.
First, let’s try to understand how we got here. Why is it that the Government of Barbados has, for a long time, been the one who sets the price of bus fare?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is Diversification Always Good?</title>
      <link>/weshouldallbeeconomists/2019/02/23/is-diversification-always-good/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/weshouldallbeeconomists/2019/02/23/is-diversification-always-good/</guid>
      <description>Diversify!
Stop putting all your eggs in one basket!
Venture into new forms of business. Don’t invest in one thing.
This is great advice for large economies. But is it useful for small economies?
It depends on how you view the world. There are two perceptions of how businesses work.
As you increase the size of your business, average costs increase As you increase the size of your business, average costs decrease  Which one do you think it is?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who Owns the Government?</title>
      <link>/weshouldallbeeconomists/2018/11/30/who-owns-the-government/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/weshouldallbeeconomists/2018/11/30/who-owns-the-government/</guid>
      <description>In 2013, the Barbados Water Authority decided to build a spanking new 63 million dollar building—without our consent. And it’s now costing you $1 million a month. The Barbados Water Authority is $500 million in debt.
 Why did they need a new 80,000 square foot building when the lovely people of St Joseph were pleading for a glass of water, for a shower, for the basic human right to water and sanitation?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Failure to Invest</title>
      <link>/weshouldallbeeconomists/2018/10/28/failure-to-invest/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/weshouldallbeeconomists/2018/10/28/failure-to-invest/</guid>
      <description>Barbados’ giant economic hole is entirely of our own making. Our distress stems from one fatal flaw: we do not invest.
Let me make it plain. Investment in new businesses, new technologies, and new ideas is the only way to generate sustainable economic growth. Economic growth is not just an economist’s foolish cravings. Economic growth is the only path to prosperity. Investment is needed for economic growth, and without economic growth, we perish.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Undefeatable Budget Constraint</title>
      <link>/weshouldallbeeconomists/2018/10/24/the-undefeatable-budget-constraint/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/weshouldallbeeconomists/2018/10/24/the-undefeatable-budget-constraint/</guid>
      <description>Imagine a Barbados that has no government. Imagine a Barbados that has never had a government. Now imagine that today, we elected our very first prime minister—you. Your job is now to build a government from scratch. You decide what we need, and how to finance it.
Take a few minutes to think.
Re-imagine Barbados. How would you design it? What would the government actually need to do? Be original. Think only of exactly what the country needs, not what it currently has.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Life, Debt, and Default</title>
      <link>/weshouldallbeeconomists/2018/06/22/life-debt-and-default/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/weshouldallbeeconomists/2018/06/22/life-debt-and-default/</guid>
      <description>Life, debt, and now default. Barbados has reached the final stage of its illness. This isn’t our sob story. This is the tale of how we got here. This post isn’t a eulogy—it’s a lesson, a warning to our future selves.
The reason the government has defaulted on the country’s public debt is simple: the government just doesn’t have enough money to both keep paying back its loans and keep the country’s services running.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Protect Workers, Not Jobs</title>
      <link>/weshouldallbeeconomists/2018/05/30/protect-workers-not-jobs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/weshouldallbeeconomists/2018/05/30/protect-workers-not-jobs/</guid>
      <description>How would you feel if you lost your job? What if your job was taken by a computer, or a machine? I think you would be angry. I know I would be mad.
But our world changes quickly. We either change with it, or get left behind. Sometimes innovation changes the world so quickly that it knocks us down. And the fear of being knocked down might be holding us back.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creative Destruction</title>
      <link>/weshouldallbeeconomists/2018/05/01/creative-destruction/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/weshouldallbeeconomists/2018/05/01/creative-destruction/</guid>
      <description>“Just because something works doesn’t mean it can’t be improved.” ~ Princess Shuri, Wakanda
 It was somewhere during my third watching of Black Panther that I realised what attracted me to Wakanda The Economy. It was the willingness to innovate, the desire for constant improvement, the idea that there’s always a better way. Overseen by a child or not, Wakanda’s technological advances were never-ending.
Why is Barbados, unlike Wakanda, so resistant to innovation?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We Should All Be Economists</title>
      <link>/weshouldallbeeconomists/2018/04/10/wsabe/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/weshouldallbeeconomists/2018/04/10/wsabe/</guid>
      <description>This blog is titled We Should All Be Economists because its purpose is to help you become an economist. Not a full-fledged practicing economist, but an engaged citizen who can discuss the merits of government policies and personal actions. This blog is to help you understand the silly economicky world around us, in real time.
We Should All Be Economists is driven by the idea that a more engaged, informed, and active society leads to better economic outcomes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s the Real Problem with Barbados?</title>
      <link>/weshouldallbeeconomists/2018/04/10/productivitybb/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/weshouldallbeeconomists/2018/04/10/productivitybb/</guid>
      <description>How have we managed to end up here again? It would be convenient to find a single person, party or group to blame. But convenience rarely points us to the truth, and what we face today is a far more fundamental failure of our society.
What is the fundamental economic problem? In a word: productivity. It’s one of those ethereal concepts that economists love to throw around. There’s plenty we don’t know about productivity, but there is plenty we agree on.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>