<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Simon Naitram</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Simon Naitram</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Who Owns the Government?</title>
      <link>/weshouldallbeeconomists/2018/11/30/who-owns-the-government/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/weshouldallbeeconomists/2018/11/30/who-owns-the-government/</guid>
      <description>In 2013, the Barbados Water Authority decided to build a spanking new 63 million dollar building—without our consent. And it’s now costing you $1 million a month. The Barbados Water Authority is $500 million in debt.
 Why did they need a new 80,000 square foot building when the lovely people of St Joseph were pleading for a glass of water, for a shower, for the basic human right to water and sanitation?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Failure to Invest</title>
      <link>/weshouldallbeeconomists/2018/10/28/failure-to-invest/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/weshouldallbeeconomists/2018/10/28/failure-to-invest/</guid>
      <description>Barbados’ giant economic hole is entirely of our own making. Our distress stems from one fatal flaw: we do not invest.
Let me make it plain. Investment in new businesses, new technologies, and new ideas is the only way to generate sustainable economic growth. Economic growth is not just an economist’s foolish cravings. Economic growth is the only path to prosperity. Investment is needed for economic growth, and without economic growth, we perish.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Undefeatable Budget Constraint</title>
      <link>/weshouldallbeeconomists/2018/10/24/the-undefeatable-budget-constraint/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/weshouldallbeeconomists/2018/10/24/the-undefeatable-budget-constraint/</guid>
      <description>Imagine a Barbados that has no government. Imagine a Barbados that has never had a government. Now imagine that today, we elected our very first prime minister—you. Your job is now to build a government from scratch. You decide what we need, and how to finance it.
Take a few minutes to think.
Re-imagine Barbados. How would you design it? What would the government actually need to do? Be original. Think only of exactly what the country needs, not what it currently has.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Life, Debt, and Default</title>
      <link>/weshouldallbeeconomists/2018/06/22/life-debt-and-default/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/weshouldallbeeconomists/2018/06/22/life-debt-and-default/</guid>
      <description>Life, debt, and now default. Barbados has reached the final stage of its illness. This isn’t our sob story. This is the tale of how we got here. This post isn’t a eulogy—it’s a lesson, a warning to our future selves.
The reason the government has defaulted on the country’s public debt is simple: the government just doesn’t have enough money to both keep paying back its loans and keep the country’s services running.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Protect Workers, Not Jobs</title>
      <link>/weshouldallbeeconomists/2018/05/30/protect-workers-not-jobs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/weshouldallbeeconomists/2018/05/30/protect-workers-not-jobs/</guid>
      <description>How would you feel if you lost your job? What if your job was taken by a computer, or a machine? I think you would be angry. I know I would be mad.
But our world changes quickly. We either change with it, or get left behind. Sometimes innovation changes the world so quickly that it knocks us down. And the fear of being knocked down might be holding us back.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creative Destruction</title>
      <link>/weshouldallbeeconomists/2018/05/01/creative-destruction/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/weshouldallbeeconomists/2018/05/01/creative-destruction/</guid>
      <description>“Just because something works doesn’t mean it can’t be improved.” ~ Princess Shuri, Wakanda
 It was somewhere during my third watching of Black Panther that I realised what attracted me to Wakanda The Economy. It was the willingness to innovate, the desire for constant improvement, the idea that there’s always a better way. Overseen by a child or not, Wakanda’s technological advances were never-ending.
Why is Barbados, unlike Wakanda, so resistant to innovation?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We Should All Be Economists</title>
      <link>/weshouldallbeeconomists/2018/04/10/wsabe/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/weshouldallbeeconomists/2018/04/10/wsabe/</guid>
      <description>This blog is titled We Should All Be Economists because its purpose is to help you become an economist. Not a full-fledged practicing economist, but an engaged citizen who can discuss the merits of government policies and personal actions. This blog is to help you understand the silly economicky world around us, in real time.
We Should All Be Economists is driven by the idea that a more engaged, informed, and active society leads to better economic outcomes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s the Real Problem with Barbados?</title>
      <link>/weshouldallbeeconomists/2018/04/10/productivitybb/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/weshouldallbeeconomists/2018/04/10/productivitybb/</guid>
      <description>How have we managed to end up here again? It would be convenient to find a single person, party or group to blame. But convenience rarely points us to the truth, and what we face today is a far more fundamental failure of our society.
What is the fundamental economic problem? In a word: productivity. It’s one of those ethereal concepts that economists love to throw around. There’s plenty we don’t know about productivity, but there is plenty we agree on.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>